- 前情提示  - 我们会带你离开这的
- Previously on Prison Break... - We're gonna get you out of here.
- 逃跑开始了  - 走走走
- The escape is on. - Go, go, go!
这人谁啊
Who the hell is the guy?
他是我哥哥
He's my brother.
你还不能死  迈克尔  你还没告诉我
Can't die on me now, Michael, you know, you're gonna tell me
- 为什么我是你的执鞭右手  - 我们找到了迈克尔
- why I'm your whip hand. - We found Michael.
- 他现在情况很糟  - 我得走了
- He's been busted up real bad. - I got to go.
你根本不知道去了会发生什么
You don't know what you'd be walking into.
太危险了
It's not safe.
我不能直视我儿子的眼睛
I can't look my son in the eye
告诉他我眼睁睁放任他爸爸死掉
and tell him that I let his father die,
他素未谋面的爸爸
a father he's never met.
从未想过我还能再见到你的脸
Never thought I'd see this face again.
你本来就不该见到
You weren't supposed to.
林肯・巴罗斯
Lincoln Burrows.
不如你站出来
How about you step out
把欠我们的十万美金还了
and pay us the 100 grand you owe us.
- 你内心很高尚  林肯  - 你应该好好休息
- There is nobility in you, Lincoln. - You should rest up.
- 我们会需要你的  - 没想到你还会担心我
- We're gonna need you. - Didn't know you worried.
这是应该的
About the right things.
怎么了
What's wrong?
他  你老公
It's him. Your husband.
雅各布
Jacob
就是波塞冬
is Poseidon.
他是CIA特务
He's a CIA operative,
深度卧底  他操纵了CIA的一个秘密分支
deep cover. He runs a splinter cell
叫21空室
called 21-Void.
他看中了我的技能
He targeted me for my skills.
迈克尔  我们儿子现在和他在一起呢
Michael, he's with our son right now.
我得尽快赶回美国
I'll get to the States as soon as I can.
是我的老公  雅各布・内斯
Did my husband, Jacob Ness,
请你查看我手机的吗
ask you to work on my cell phone?
他说他想要找出
He said he was looking to find
跟踪她老婆的人
the people who were stalking
所以我对手机进行了深度数据搜索
his wife, so I did a data dive.
我儿子呢
Where's my son?
在我这
I have him.
我是否对他构成威胁
And whether or not I have to threaten him
全取决于你是否放下枪
is entirely contingent upon you putting the gun down.
科尼尔・奥提斯
Kaniel Outis
目前定位在一艘
has been located on a cargo ship
行驶在地中海上的货轮上
in the Mediterranean.
是他们改变了你
They made you.
快跑
Run!
在这里
Hey!
救命
哥们
Hey, yo,
我们在往哪开
where we headed?
马赛市
Marseille.
- 马赛市  - 马赛市
- Marseilles. - Marseilles.
你的命是我的  斯科菲尔德
I own you, Scofield.
我对你了如指掌
I know everything about you.
甚至包括你最平常的活动  比如逛动物园
Even your most mundane actions, like the zoo.
为什么你总去动物园
What's with you and the zoo?
我可以去那里思考
I go there to think.
上个月去了十八次
18 times in the past month?
我想了很多  我在想如何带你们
A lot of thinking. I was figuring out how to get
逃出巴兰基亚
your guy out of Barranquilla.
看来他并不只是个叛军领导
Turns out he's not just a rebel leader...
他还是个残忍的反社会者
He's a murderous sociopath.
没办法  我们现在需要他
That's the only way to make omelets.
我需要了解目标的更多信息
I need to know more about our targets.
如果让我帮他越狱  必须万无一失
If I'm facilitating escapes, we can't have surprises.
我们应该为此而自豪
Be proud. You and me,
- 我们在改变世界  - 那不代表这就是对的
- we're changing the world. - Doesn't make it right.
别装的好像你突然很满足现状一样
Don't act like you're suddenly a fan of the status quo, okay?
现在的法治系统  非常缓慢  笨拙  注定要玩完
The system, it's slow, stupid, and doomed to fail.
这就是为什么你一开始要救出你哥哥
That's why you had to bust your brother out in the first place.
又纹了新的纹身
New ink since the last time I saw you.
- 有新的计划了  - 不  没新计划
- Working on a new plan? - No. No new plan.
只是不想让那块皮空着
Just get tired of looking at empty skin.
你知道吗  我一开始就是被你在福克斯河监狱
You know, it was those tats at Fox River
纹的纹身吸引的
that caught my eye in the first place.
我对这个把计划纹在身上的男人
I had to know everything about the man
非常的好奇
who wore his plans on his skin.
显而易见却又十分神秘的纹身
In plain sight yet so mysterious.
真正的强者善于隐藏自己
The key to real power is to disappear.
- 内斯教授  - 你好  克罗地亚
- Hi, Professor Ness. - Hello, Claudia.
真正的强者
Yeah, the secret to real power
从不背叛自己的本意
is to never betray your intentions,
却又会隐藏自己的情绪
to wear nothing on your sleeve.
不让任何人
And to never let anyone
看到你的真面目
see your face.
进来吧
Come on in.
下次我被关进单间时
Next time I'm sitting in solitary,
我会想到这里的你  在舒服的空调房
I'll think of you in here, running the world
操控着世界
in air-conditioned comfort.
我也曾去打过仗
I've spent my time in the field.
你准备好去缅甸了吗
You all set for Myanmar?
就剩下几周了
It's only a few weeks off.
这就是我来这的原因
That's why I'm here.
我想再加一个帮手
I want to bring someone on board.
- 真的吗  - 实兑市的战俘营
- Oh, really? - The prison camp
是需要两个人才能完成的工作
at Sittwe is a two-man job.
我观察一个人很久了  他会派上用场的
I've been watching this guy. He'll be useful.
观察他  你现在负责
Watching him? You in charge
- 招人了  - 相信我
- of recruiting now? - Trust me.
我根本不想再拖一个人下水了
The last thing I was to do is suck someone else into this.
他可以帮助我  这样更有效率
He'll have my back and he'll speed things up,
增加逃脱的几率
increase our odds.
并未从事什么特别的职业
Not exactly a distinguished career.
他现在被好好的关在监狱里  他挺有脾气的
He's held up well in prison. He's got a mean streak.
而且他孑然一身
And he grew up without a family.
说明他可以被操控
It means he can be manipulated.
不管你在计划什么
If you're planning something,
我总能先你一步
I'll always be a step ahead of you.
你知道的
You know that.
我可以从你眼中看透一切
I can see everything in your eyes.
光看表面是不够的
It's what's behind the eyes that counts,
教授
Professor.
所以你打算用一年时间
So you're gonna wait a year
等我从实兑市逃出来
for me to find my way out of Sittwe?
还是你让我带上个同伴
Or are you gonna get me a partner,
这样我们能快点步入正轨  改变世界
so we get on with the business of changing the world?
成交
Done.
我想吃东东
I need some food.
我也是
I'm with you.
林肯  萨拉的短信
Linc, it's Sara.
她回到纽约了
She's back in New York.
她和小迈还好吗
Are she and Mike okay?
这正是我想问的
That's what I'm trying to find out.
怎么了  迈克尔
What is it, Michael?
出事了
Something's wrong.
是的  你们会的
Yes, you will.
- 我得尽快赶回美国  - 别着急
- I got to get back to the States. - Slow down.
你是科尼尔・奥提斯  记得吗
You're Kaniel Outis, remember?
你现在在世界所有禁飞名单上
You're on every no-fly list in the world.
雅各布对萨拉做了什么  也许迈克受了牵连
Jacob's done something to Sara. Maybe Mike, too.
- 你怎么知道的  - 那封短信
- How do you know? - That text.
她叫咱儿子小迈克尔
She referred to our son as Junior.
我们都同意再也不那么叫他
We agreed we'd never call him that.
他在引诱你  迈克尔
He's baiting you, Michael.
那他奏效了
It worked.
嘿  小家伙
Hey, buddy.
妈妈哪去了
Where's Mom?
我在你上学的时候
Oh. I, uh, dropped her off at work
把她送去上班了
while you were at school.
这艘海盗船真不错
That is quite a pirate ship.
然而这么靠前的桅杆
Although it would be a little hard
船想航行可有点困难
to sail with the mast that far forward.
- 你的船可能会翻  - 这桅杆必须在那
- Your ship might tip over. - The mast has
这不仅是艘船
to be there. It's not just a ship...
也是个藏宝图
It's a treasure map.
这是什么意思
What do you mean?
这是给吉米的  我们把彼此的乐高积木藏起来了
It's for Jimmy. We hide Legos for each other.
我总能找到他藏得
I always find his.
他却不是总能找到我藏的
He doesn't always find mine.
等下
Wait a second,
这怎么是在画藏宝图
how is this drawing a map?
这是个公园
This is the park.
那是游乐场
That's the playground.
而这是人行道
And this is the sidewalk.
不错嘛
Impressive.
你把谜语藏到了这幅画里
You put a code in the drawing.
那好  你把乐高积木藏在哪儿了
So, okay, where did you hide the Legos?
这些大炮是公园里的泳池
These cannons are pools at the park.
但这里多出一个大炮  在沙子里
But there's an extra one, in the sand.
那就是我藏乐高积木的地方
That's where I buried the Legos.
干得漂亮  迈克
Well done, Mike.
干得漂亮
Well done.
我打听了所有人  我在美国已经没有线人了
I've tried everyone. I'm out of resources in the States.
我所有的联系人  那些可以去看看他们
All my contacts. People who can go and check on them,
确保他们没事的人
make sure they're okay.
林肯  我必须回趟家
Linc, I got to get home.
我不能再花两个礼拜待在货船上
I can't spend another two weeks on a cargo ship.
他手上有我老婆孩子
He's got my wife and kid.
也许有别的办法
There may be another way.
你跟我讲了你最近七年的生活
You told me about the last seven years of your life.
我还没跟你讲我的生活
Haven't told you about mine.
在萨拉被免罪之后  她离开了巴拿马
After Sara got exonerated, she left Panama.
我和索菲亚留在那里开了一家潜水用品店
Me and Sofia stayed behind and opened a dive shop.
我们分手后  一切都变糟了
We broke up, and everything went to hell.
你当时没在场阻止我  所以不知不觉中
You weren't there to stop me, so before I knew it,
我就在那片老邻里  打些零工
I was in the old hood, doing odd jobs.
打些零工是什么意思
Odd jobs meaning what?
帮卢卡・阿布鲁齐
Moving things from point A to point B.
运送东西
For Luca Abruzzi.
阿布老大的儿子
John Abruzzi's son.
是的
Yeah.
我只想赚点块钱  重整旗鼓
I just wanted some quick cash to kick-start my life.
他们跟我说不要看箱子里的东西
They told me not to look in the boxes.
但我还是看了
But I looked in the boxes.
他们从欧洲走私来的一大包芬太尼毒品
The amount of fentanyl they're smuggling out of Europe...
一盒有成千上万片药
Tens of thousands of pills in every box...
害人不浅
It's just killing people.
我把一个盒子扔进了垃圾箱
So I dumped a box in a Dumpster,
里面的药值十万美金
100 grand's worth.
现在你欠阿布老大的儿子钱
Now you're in hock to Abruzzi's son.
是啊  他想杀死我
Yeah. He wants to kill me.
但也许这是个能快点回到美国的办法
But maybe it's a way to get back to the States real fast.
你挺有胆量嘛  巴罗斯
You got balls, Burrows.
你真的觉得我愿意帮你吗
You actually think I want to help you?
如果我能给你十万美元呢
What if I can get you the $100K?
10万美元吗
$100K?
你打算怎么还
How are you gonna come up with that
你还在芝加哥的黑巷里摸爬滚打
crawling around the back alleys of Chicago?
我不在芝加哥  我在马赛
I'm not in Chicago. I'm in Marseilles.
- 你在马赛吗  - 是的
- Marseilles? - Yeah.
我最近在进行两笔交易  手头上有十万美金
I've been working on a couple deals. I got $100K
但我带着它逃跑了
in my hand. But I want off the hook.
你当然会这么要求  你过来亲自给我钱怎么样
Sure you do. How about you get over here and hand it to me?
这就是我打电话来的原因
That's why I'm calling.
我需要神不知鬼不觉的去美国  像你的药那样
I need to sneak into the States invisible, like your pills.
你那些从欧洲起飞的航班
Those flights you got coming out of Europe...
那些藏着芬太尼的航班  我需要几个座位
The fentanyl flights... I need a few seats.
行
I'll tell you what.
我会打几通电话
I'll make a few calls.
要么让我见你拿着钱
'Cause either I'm gonna see you
否则
and get that money, or I'm gonna see you,
后果自负
and you're gonna get something a whole lot worse.
我不敢相信自己又惹这样的麻烦了
I can't believe I'm doing this to myself again.
不同的是这一次  你不再孤身一人
Difference is this time, you're not alone.
天啊  这些东西真恶心
God, these things are disgusting.
他们管这东西叫什么来着
What they call 'em again?
法国血肠
Boudin noir.
不确定是什么做的
Not sure what's in them.
我不觉得你的法语像你想的那样好
I don't think your French is as good as you think it is.
嘿  开心点  你又不是在吃蜗牛
Yo, be happy you're not eating snails.
嘿
Hey.
你觉得他们察觉到了吗
Do you think they noticed?
咱还是别冒险
Let's not take any chances.
伙计们
Guys.
新闻上到处都是你们的脸
Your faces were on the news.
要是有人认出你们了  就完蛋了
Somebody sees you, this thing is over.
- 我们得走了  老大  -  我们得走了
- We got to move, papi. - We got to go.
等下  卢卡
Hold. Luca.
如果你午夜前能到里昂
If you can get to Lyon by midnight,
我能让你上飞机
I can get you on a flight.
我在纽约有个仓库  你会来找我吗
I got a warehouse in New York. You're coming to me?
我们会的
We'll be there.
我不知道我是不是
Can't decide whether I want you
真想要那钱了  巴罗斯
to have that money or not, Burrows.
杀了你会更让我满足
Killing you might be a lot more satisfying.
现在我们知道他们在地中海行动中活下来了
Now we know they survived the strike in the Mediterranean.
我们基本可以确定他会回伊萨卡
We can be pretty sure he's coming back to Ithaca.
我需要一些解释
I need some clarification.
他为什么会选择回来
Why would he come back here...
全世界
to the States
通缉他力度
when he's more wanted here
最强的美国
than anywhere else in the world?
当然了
Of course.
他这么选择是因为他们
Because of them.
他在为我工作之前有自己的生活
He had a life before he worked for me,
也有自己的名字  迈克尔・斯科菲尔德
a name... Michael Scofield.
也有家室
A family.
当他逃跑之后  我就去找了他家人
And when he went away, I ended up looking after them.
最后  我爱上了他老婆
Ended up... falling for them.
现在嘛
Well...
他想杀了我
He wants to kill me.
他认为我窃取了他的生活  毁了他这个人
He thinks I stole his life, ruined him, which speaks
他是个反社会分子
to his dissociative mind.
我是说  他是个杀人犯  一个叛徒  一个恐怖分子
I mean, he's a murderer, a turncoat, a terrorist.
但我们要利用他这一点
But we'll use it.
如果必要的话我会去当诱饵
I'll be the bait if I have to.
然后我们就能一劳永逸的拿下他
So we can go about taking him down once and for all.
他不是来闲逛的
He's not just gonna stroll in here.
他太聪明了
He's too clever for that.
不过我们有个更聪明的人
That's why we got someone even more clever.
索罗
Thoreau?
那人一点前途没有
Guy's a pencil neck.
一个没前途但是熟悉斯科菲尔德的计划
A pencil neck with insight into Scofield's plan.
这样反过来  你占取主动权
So you, in turn, can be the hammer.
这是他从沙漠发的
Screen-grab of the Skype transmission
网络视频传输的截图
he sent from the desert.
他把图片通过服务器发送给
He routed the image through a server
这个蓝色夏威夷  但也有可能
to this BlueHawaii guy, but it could have been
同时发送给另一个人
secretly subrouted to another, yet
一个未知的接收者来使用这些加密的信息
unknown, recipient to use the information encoded in it.
信息
Information?
这简直难以置信
It's actually incredible.
通过阿拉伯语加密  这些图形五花八门
Encrypted in the Arabic, the images are all sorts of stuff.
显而易见的是  无聊至极
Apparently, mundane as hell.
动物园的营业时间  暂停运营的
Visiting hours for zoos, links to defunct message boards
一些网络公告牌
on the Internet.
什么公告牌
What message boards?
真实之烟网  猎手营地网
Truesnuff.com, Hunterspycamporn.com,
两个网站上都有  这个
both of which carry... this.
哈伦・盖恩斯谋杀案的图片
Images of the Harlan Gaines murder.
这个混蛋为什么把这个玩意儿又找出来了
What's the bastard doing rubbing that in our faces?
这么多需要解密的  为什么是这个
Of all the things to encrypt, why that?
这有什么帮助
What's that get you?
从图像数据加密角度来说  帮助很大
Stegaonographically, a lot.
图像数据加密是一种在数字文件的编码中
Steganography is the practice of concealing information
隐藏信息的技术
in the code that makes up digital files.
俄国在搞这个  中国也是  都在研究
Russians do it, Chinese, everybody.
他八成在想  要是有人看到这个
He's probably thinking if anyone sees this,
并不会仔细研究
this'll be as far as they'll look.
但是我已经进入图像内部  解密这些
But I'm already going inside the image, breaking down the data
- 组成这个的数据  - 一听这些我就头晕
- that comprises it. - This is making my head spin.
关键是要用大数据处理  人工智能
Point is we put big data, AI on this,
我们就可以把这里隐藏的信息尽快破解
we can crunch any codes hidden in there pretty quickly.
我也是正在加油
And that's what I'm doing.
干得不错  但是问题在于  如果我这头搞定了
Nice work, but the truth is if I've done my job,
他也许会主动把他的意图暴露出来
he may reveal his intentions to us first.
因为我已经把他的计划打乱了
Because I've got him so far off his game now,
他就会过早的进行他的下一个锦囊妙计
he'll start to play his cards too early...
泰迪
Teddy.
但是为了回报  你必须去杀一个人
"But in return, you must take a life."
也会在电脑破解之前
show us what the tattoos mean
告诉我们纹身的意思  还有
even before the computers will, and all the people
所有他准备为战斗招募的人
he'll be enlisting for the fight.
你必须去打这个
You have to call this pay phone
在法国的公用电话
in France.
等等  芝加哥  我以为我要跟你一起走
Wait. Chicago? I thought I was going with you.
你得先搞明白为什么你是我的执鞭之手
Not until you find out why you're my whip-hand.
我非得去芝加哥才能搞明白
I have to go to Chicago to find that out?
一路顺风
Safe travels.
他的计划太过宏伟
In the grandiosity of his plan,
以至于他会看漏最小的细节
he'll lose sight of the simplest details.
他给我发消息的手机
The phone he texted me with
昨晚在法国里昂
was located in Lyon, France last night.
在晚上十一点五十一分在机场关机
It was turned off in an airport terminal at 11:51 p.m...
在一趟直飞纽约的飞机起飞前二十分钟
20 minutes before a direct flight to New York where
在那里等着他
you'll be waiting for him
结束这场游戏
to put this game to bed for good.
290号航班飞往佛罗里达迈阿密
Flight 290 to Miami, Florida
即将从B24登机口起飞
will now depart from gate B24.
他又开机了
He just powered back up.
我们找到他了
We got him.
小心
Look out!
飞机后部
Back of the plane.
呃  不好意思  不好意思
Uh, excuse me! Excuse me.
你不能
You're not allowed...
看来游戏还得继续
Looks like the game's still going.
真是厉害  你可以通过
It's impressive how you get these drugs
贿赂一些机场临时工
in the country just by bribing small-time
就把这些毒品带入境
airport officials.
我猜这里有
I'm guessing you got about
价值五百万美金的芬太尼
five million bucks worth of fentanyl in here.
所以呢
So what?
你和你哥打算给我上课么
You and your brother here are gonna lecture me?
我们在考虑要不要
We were actually debating on whether
把这十万块给你
I should give you the 100K or not.
他说这钱来的太脏
He says it's blood money.
- 我也同意  - 你为什么不闭嘴付钱就行  巴罗斯
- I agree. - ?How about you just shut up and pay me, Burrows?
我没带
I don't have it.
抓住这几个  带到后面给我毙了
Grab his guys, bring 'em to the back and shoot 'em.
我不觉得你会想在自己的逮捕令上加上谋杀罪
I don't think you want to add murder to your arrest warrant.
等等
Wait.
逮捕令
Arrest warrant?
外面那家伙
That guy out there
是禁毒执法局的线人
is a DEA informant.
他是我们的人
We have him in our pocket.
他欠我们的  一个电话
He owes us. He's got three vans
他就能给你叫来三车特警
full of agents that are waiting for his call.
他们会把你和你的毒品射成筛子
They're gonna rain down on you and your pills.
除非  你免除我哥哥的债务
Unless you forgive my brother's debt.
我们的线人就不会打电话
Then our informant won't make the call.
让你弟弟给你出头  是不
Have your brother fighting your battles, do you?
不
No.
为什么不让你的小伙子们把枪放下
Why don't you tell your guys to drop the guns,
咱俩来解决解决问题
and you and I can have it out?
怎么说  卢卡
What do you say, Luca?
把那个家伙赶走
Scare that guy off.
把这几个人带到后面
Bring these guys to the back.
他们敢动一下  他就打电话
They make a move, he makes a call.
是么  我觉得你在唬人
Yeah? I think you're bluffing.
我警告过你
I warned you.
来人了
We got company.
敢开枪  这里有一堆的证人
You shoot us, there's dozens of witnesses now.
我们撤
Let's go.
他们只需要看见禁毒执法局的帽子和黑越野车
All they had to see were DEA hats and SUVs,
然后就跑了
and they were gone.
大名鼎鼎的迈克尔・斯科菲尔德
Famous Michael Scofield.
谢巴  感谢你做的一切
Sheba. Thank you for everything.
你绝对想不到我有多开心看到你回家
You have no idea how happy I am to see you back home.
我们还没到家呢
We're not home yet.
好了  下一步呢
All right, so what's next?
我们怎么抓住这个狗娘养的
How do we get this son of a bitch?
我们什么都不做
We don't do anything.
你的部分结束了
Your part is over.
不  不  不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no, no.
糊弄阿布老大的孩子是一回事
Tricking Abruzzi's kid is one thing.
波塞冬  他认识你
Poseidon... he knows your face.
自从到了也门就一直追踪你
Been tracking you since you went to Yemen.
你是个勇士
You've been a warrior,
我欠你的
and I owe you.
但是你的相貌会成为你和你家庭的累赘
But your face is a liability now to you and your family.
我不想让你陷入风险
I don't want you to risk that.
他们也许认识他  但是不认识我
They may know his face, but they don't know mine.
明枪易躲暗箭难防
It's the punch you don't see coming that knocks you out.
这才是我的谢巴
That's my Sheba.
照顾好她  行么
You take care of her, all right?
不应该是我照顾好他么
I take care of him, you mean.
- 我爱你  哥们  - 我也爱你
- I love you, brother. - Love you, too.
一路小心
Be safe,
- 好么  - 你也是
- okay? - You, too.
- 再见  - 好了
- Bye. - All right.
好了
Well...
如果再次需要我
when you need me again,
你知道到哪里找我
you know where to find me.
我们下午四点转移她
We'll transport her at 1600 hours.
在那之前  低调一点  谢谢
Lay low until then. Thank you.
嘿
Hey?
你不觉得难受么  刚才看到那些
That doesn't bother you... What you just saw in there?
地下室里是他的老婆
Down in the basement
他声称深爱的人
with his wife, the woman he says he fell for?
停
Stop.
在这结束后  我就退出21空室了
I'm done with 21-Void after this.
自从我们找到了斯科菲尔德  奥提斯
After we get Scofield... Outis...
不管他叫什么名
Whatever his name is...
我都退出
I'm done.
我的目的只是  找到杀盖恩斯的凶手
That's all I ever wanted, to get Gaines' killer, but
但是他在里面所做的事
what he's got going in there...
十分不正常
That's not normal.
是私人的
It's personal.
有些恶心
Something sicker.
万  你知道的  不能离开21空室
There's no leaving 21-Void, Van. You know that.
他肯雇用我们  因为我们是最好的
He hired us because we are the best.
我们可以做任何他让我们做的事
We can do whatever we want.
如果我们之后想销声匿迹额
And if we want to disappear after this...
我们就可以销声匿迹
we can disappear.
但我们没法退出的
There's no getting out.
如果你这么想的话
If you think that way...
那么你也是个囚犯
then you're a prisoner, too.
门口的人说他们到这五分钟之后
The guy at the gate said the vehicles split
车就坏了
five minutes after they got here.
五分钟
Five minutes?
有些不对劲
Something ain't right.
东西还在那
The product is still here.
来
Come on.
一切都开始了
It was all staged.
聪明
Clever.
但是巴罗斯会因此而死
But Burrows is gonna die for it.
我不知道怎么找到他
I don't know how we're gonna find him.
他神龙见首不见尾
He's in the wind.
也许不是
Maybe not.
通关转发器
EZ Pass transponders.
圣托拉在边检处发现一个人
Santora's got a guy at transit authority.
我敢打赌他能告诉我们那帮人什么时候走了哪条路
I bet you he can tell us what roads they've been taking and when.
之后什么时候收拾他们就是我们说的算了
Then it's up to us to comb the neighborhoods,
把车找到
find the vehicles,
然后开枪把那个贱人还有他同伴们都弄死
and put a bullet in that son of a bitch once and for all.
_
请您时刻看管好随身物品
Please keep your baggage with you at all times.
无人看管的行李存在风险  可能导致
Unattended baggage is a security risk and may result...
我有个奇怪的请求
I got a weird request.
我给你几个坐标  你能带我找到他们吗
If I give you some coordinates, can you take me to 'em?
我试试
See what I can do.
不能
No.
除非这车能在水里开
Unless this cab's got pontoons,
不然没法找到
ain't gonna happen.
这些坐标位于密歇根湖中部
These coordinates are in the middle of Lake Michigan.
这里就是了
This is it.
没开灯
No lights.
迈克尔  我觉得他们不在
I don't think they're here, Michael.
除非他故意让我们这样觉得
Unless that's what he wants us to think.
走吧
Come on.
准备好以最快的速度带我们离开这里
Get ready to get us out of here as fast as you can.
林肯
Linc.
小心点
Be careful.
谢谢
Thanks.
怎么了
What's wrong?
这就是萨拉从不回复我的原因
That's why Sara never responded.
我不能联系任何人
I wasn't allowed to contact anyone,
但她是我的妻子
but she was my wife.
我用了一种我认为
I reached out to her in a way
只有她懂的方式联系她
I thought only she would know.
但是他也知道这种方法
But he knew my ways, too.
没人
Nothing.
我在伊萨卡
你在干什么
What are you doing?
那个人不是萨拉  迈克尔
That's not Sara, Michael.
他不知道我发现了
He doesn't know I know that.
谢天谢地  你和迈克能明天再走吗
好啊  我们去哪  还记得我欠你的那顿晚餐吗
去Filet Mignon餐厅好吗  雪城的牛排店吗  中午见
答对了
- _ - That's the right answer.
她还活着
She's alive.
他肯定和她在一起
He must be right there with her.
我会安排个会面
I'm gonna set a meeting.
然后呢  你要直接过去现身
And what, you're just gonna show up and show your face?
是的
Yes.
那也意味着波塞冬也得现身了
That means Poseidon has to show his face, too.
最后的游戏即将开始
And the endgame begins.
大中午了  老板
It's high noon, boss.
没看见他
I'm not seeing him.
不应该这样的  他正等着我们
And you shouldn't. He's waiting for us
先走出第一步
to push the first piece out onto the board.
所以由我负责第一步吗
Which would be me?
也许不是
Maybe not.
黑色的SUV车
Black SUV.
有什么需要帮忙的吗
Something I can help you with?
接送服务  我来这接一个女人和一个小孩
Car service. I'm here to pick up a lady and child.
他们坐别的车了  滚吧
They got another ride. Hit the road.
确定吗
Are you sure?
快滚
Hit the road.
追踪这辆黑色SUV
Mark the black SUV.
不用  他们只是想让你现身而已
No need. They were just here to make you show your face.
走开吧  马上
Walk away, please. Now.
好吧  表现得谨小慎微一些
Okay, act the tiniest bit flustered.
现在给我用最大声重复我说的话  让别人都能听到
Now repeat these words back to me loud enough to be heard:
他们没出现
"They didn't show.
我现在回你那儿去
I'm coming back to you now."
他们没出现
They didn't show.
我现在回你那儿去
I'm coming back to you now.
现在我们有的玩儿了
Now we have a game.
他已经暴露了他最重要的部分
He's already revealed
他的哥哥
his brother, his biggest piece.
很快他就会现身了  跟着
Soon he'll have to show his face. Trailer,
把他拿下
please take him down.
什么
What the...?
我跟丢了
I lost him.
嘿
Hey.
能听到吗
Can you hear me?
该死
Damn it.
没信号
No signal.
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
我在车库跟丢了目标
I lost reception in the garage.
见鬼  你正合他们心意
Damn it, you fell right into it.
他们现在可以反追踪我们了
Now they've got a mark on us.
黑色轿车
Black sedan.
他往西开了
He's heading west.
求你了
Please!
求你了  别开枪
Please, don't shoot.
你还好吗
You okay?
这就是毁了我国家的狗
So that's what the dog who's destroying my country
的下场
looks like.
跟我说说
Talk to me.
迈克尔  我们发现那辆车了
Michael, we found the car.
我们在第三大街和华盛顿大道交叉口旁的小巷
We're on the corner of Third and Washington by an alley.
马上来
Get here now.
萨拉在他手里
He had Sara with him
- 但我们没看到她  - 你说没看见她是什么意思
- but we couldn't see her. - What do you mean you couldn't see her?
我们没办法看到她
There's no way we could have.
哦  天啊  萨拉
Oh, my God. Sara.
后座
There was no one
- 没人吗  - 没  窗户
- in the backseat? - No, the windows
都被挡住了  我们看不到
were blacked out... We couldn't see.
那是什么
What's that?
我儿子做的
My son did this.
他很厉害
He's good.
这里一定有什么
There might be something here.
是个小船
It's a ship.
载着三个海盗的海盗船
A pirate ship with three pirates...
男人  女人  和一个小男孩
Man, woman and a boy.
这是我  萨拉和迈克
That's me, Sara and... Mike.
你觉得这个是什么呢
What do you think that is?
这是  这是一种多个头的九头虫
It's a... it's a many-headed hydra
正在抬首攻击
reaching up to attack.
这代表雅各布吗
Think it's Jacob?
肯定是
Must be.
- 这是一条信息  - 你觉得迈克画的
- This is a message. - You're telling me
这些东西是一种密码吗
Mikey's left something encoded in that?
是的  是的  这就是他的密码
Yeah. Yeah, it's encoded in him.
他有着我的血脉
He's got my DNA.
他甚至都不知道你要来啊
He didn't even know you were coming.
肯定是萨拉告诉他的  我不知道
Sara must have told him. I don't know.
她肯定告诉他我就要回来了
She must have told him I was coming.
这里绝对代表着什么信息  绝对有
There's definitely something here. Definitely.
那是谁
What is it?
那家伙是卢卡的人
It's one of Luca's guys.
什么
What?
他他妈的要在这儿攻击我们吗
How the hell did he track us here?
我不知道  我知道的只是
I don't know. All I know is all the chickens
总是会屋漏偏逢连夜雨
are coming home to roost at the worst possible time.
我们得走了
We got to go.
林肯
Linc?
我知道了
I got it.
这条船  这艘帆船
This ship, this galleon.
这个水的形状有意义  我在地图上找到了
The body of water it's on. I looked at the map.
这是一个湖  一个形状一样的湖
There's a lake, a lake shaped exactly like it,
就在手指湖区域
up in the Finger Lakes district.
长湖
"Long lake."
这个X
This X
代表了他们就在湖的东岸
would be on the east shore of that lake.
它在告诉我们它的位置
He's telling us where he is.
我还在想  你是不是已经失去了你的理智
I'm trying to figure out if you lost your mind or not.
- 你不去  - 什么
- Uh-uh. - What?
- 你要回到布法罗  - 什么
- You're going back to Buffalo. - What?!
我想要你和你的家人呆在一起  照顾那些难民
I want you to be with your family, look after the refugees.
林肯  我现在也是这个斗争的一部分了
Linc, I'm a part of this fight, too...
这是啥意思
What was that?
这是告别吻
It's good-bye.
如果你要是出什么事情
I could never forgive myself
我是不会原谅自己的
if something happened to you.
芝加哥  伊利诺伊州
密歇根湖畔
有什么可以效劳的吗
Can I help you?
是啊
Yeah.
我能租条船吗
Can I rent a boat?
我想租一条船在湖上逛逛
I want to take one out on the lake.
曾经想过
Been thinkin'.
上帝
God...
我一直在想
I been thinking.
因为我被赠与了一个艰难的交易
'Cause a hard bargain's been presented to me,
而我正在考虑一些
and I'm considering something
一些看起来像是
that's-that's gonna seem like
老西奥多・巴格威尔的事
the old Theodore Bagwell.
T-Bag
T-Bag.
如果这确实就要发生
And if that's indeed what's coming...
这将不是一个冷血的
it won't be the work
男人干的事情
of a cold-blooded man.
也不是为了罪恶
And it won't be for sin...
或者是仇恨
or for hate.
如果我的双手沾满鲜血
If there's blood on my hands,
记住这个  世界
know this, world...
这是为了爱
it'll be for love.
你怎么样啊  兄弟
How you doing, buddy?
我很厌恶这个湖边小屋
I'm sick of the lake house.
我想回家
I want to go home.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
我们会回家的
We'll go home soon.
不用担心
Don't worry.
妈妈还好吗
Is Mom okay?
她
She's, uh...
这种天气  她有点
she's a little under the weather.
她只是在休息
She's just resting.
一切事情都会变好的  孩子
Everything will be fine, kiddo.
很快  一切都会恢复到正轨上  好吗
Everything will be back to normal soon enough, okay?
迈克尔  去找到他  我会准备好的
Michael, go get him. And I'll be ready.
- 谢了 哥们 很有趣  - 是啊  随时效劳
- Thanks, man, that was fun. - Yeah, anytime.
好的  很好  谢谢你
Yeah, great. Thank you.
鞭子算哪门子敬称
What kind of honorific is Whip?
你算哪棵葱
Who's asking?
一个被命运召唤的男人
A man drawn into this by destiny.
好吧  不如你把这件衣服脱下来
Okay. How about you take off?
我不会被一个大半夜来找我的男人
I don't exactly cotton to strange men coming up to me
给吓成棉花布袋
in the middle of the night, you know?
只有一个人能叫我鞭子  而你不是他
Only one person calls me Whip... you ain't him.
某人叫你鞭子
Nobody calls you that.
就是给我这智能义肢的人  某个人
Man who gave me this hand. Nobody.
科尼尔・奥提斯
Kaniel Outis.
或者对我们这些认识的人来说
Or for those of us who know him,
迈克尔・斯科菲尔德
Michael Scofield.
你是谁
Who are you?
我们都有别名  不是吗
We all got handles, don't we?
奥提斯  T-Bag  鞭子
Outis. T-Bag. Whip.
但你是戴维・马丁  不是吗
But you're Dave Martin, aren't you?
你怎么知道的
How'd you know that?
哈
Huh?
你最好赶紧告诉我  老头子
You better start talking, old man.
你不会想纠缠这个的
You don't want to tangle with this.
你也不用
Neither do you.
你想知道的都在这里  好吗
All your answers are right in here, all right?
西弗吉尼亚州下等酒馆
West Virginia honky-tonk,
1991年  漂亮的女服务员
1991, pretty waitress,
一堆个人业务在打烊之后发生了
bunch of personal business between us after closing,
然后我赶紧离开了  因为约翰尼・刘就这样插着我的脖子紧盯着我
and then I git, 'cause Johnny Law's breathing down my neck.
没有任何转寄地址
Lacking a forwarding address,
后来再也没听说过她
I never heard from her again.
你想告诉我什么
What are you trying to tell me?
斯科菲尔德当时在找一个合伙人  各个监狱里都找
Scofield was looking for a partner, combing prisons,
寻找一个可以帮助他的人
looking for someone who could handle himself.
随着你自己的天生的能力
And with your innate ability to thrive,
甚至可以在一个最糟的监狱里走上巅峰
rising to the top in even the worst of cages,
你让他想起了某个人
you reminded him of a certain someone.
所以他就做了点小调查
And so he did a little research.
想知道我们都想知道的什么
Wanted to know what we all want to know.
你是学来的吗
Did you learn it...
还是在你身上滋生的
or was it ingrained in you?
就是根生于你身上的  小子
It was ingrained in you, son.
你接了我的班
You got it from me.
林肯  他在这儿
Linc, he's here.
- 我的儿子  谢天谢地
- My son. - Thank God.
等会儿
Hold on.
Hold up.
我想雅克布回来了
I think Jacob's coming back.
我真不敢相信又看到了自己儿子
I can't believe I'm seeing my son.
有点儿不对劲
Something's wrong.
萨拉在这儿  但是
Sara's here, but...
- 有点儿不对劲  - 不要声张  他回来了
- something's wrong. - Don't do anything. He's coming back.
我要进去了
I'm going in.
那不是雅克布
It's not Jacob.
危机解除了
You're clear.
接上家人  接上你的儿子
Get your family. Get your son.
巴罗斯
Burrows!
你好  迈克
Hi, Mike.
你知道我是谁吗
You know who I am?
我拿到了你的地图
I got your map.
我来接你和你的妈妈一起离开
I'm gonna get you and your mother out of here.
我  我没话地图啊
I... I didn't draw a map.
- 有人和你妈妈一起在这儿吗  - 那不是
- Is someone in there with your mom? - It's not...
我们得快跑了
We need to run.
地中海某处
马赛市
法国
平安到家了  你在哪
雅各布可疑吗
不确定  但我们不能久留  太危险了
别担心  我马上就去找你了  我爱你
我也爱你  小迈克也是
伊萨卡
纽约
肯尼迪机场
威尔莫特市政机场
纽约上州
谢天谢地
你和迈克能明天再走吗
好啊  我们去哪
还记得我欠你的那顿晚餐吗
去Filet Mignon餐厅好吗
雪城的牛排店吗  中午见
长湖
但是作为回报  你必须过好自己的生活
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h--迈克尔
录音机
正在录音
越狱   第五季   重置
第   八   集
电影淘淘
WWW.DYTTBD.COM
更多电影美剧尽在（电影淘淘 www.dyttbd.com）